[GUARANTEED\* CHRISTMAS DELIVERY

Ground Ship Cutoff - **Today**, 12/18 @ 12PM CST](https://www.horizonhobby.com/shipping-billing-returns-info.html?cp_source=global&cp_medium=tippy-top)

[Holiday Gift Guide

Find The Perfect RC Gift](https://www.horizonhobby.com/holiday-headquarters/?cp_source=global&cp_medium=tippy-top)

[GUARANTEED\* CHRISTMAS DELIVERY

Ground Ship Cutoff - **Today**, 12/18 @ 12PM CST](https://www.horizonhobby.com/shipping-billing-returns-info.html?cp_source=global&cp_medium=tippy-top)

[Holiday Gift Guide

Find The Perfect RC Gift](https://www.horizonhobby.com/holiday-headquarters/?cp_source=global&cp_medium=tippy-top)

Search Name or Part Number

 icon-close

Support

Support

 Sign In

Sign In for the best experience.

Create an account [here.](https://www.horizonhobby.com/login?action=register)

Sign In 

My Account

    0

Cart

  [  0

Cart](https://www.horizonhobby.com/cart "Cart 0 Item(s)")

Cart | 0 Item(s)

Your cart is empty. [Start shopping](https://www.horizonhobby.com/) now!

air

ground

water

  [  0](https://www.horizonhobby.com/cart "Cart 0 Item(s)")

[My store

Select A Store](javascript:void(0))

My store

[GUARANTEED\* CHRISTMAS DELIVERY

Ground Ship Cutoff - **Today**, 12/18 @ 12PM CST](https://www.horizonhobby.com/shipping-billing-returns-info.html?cp_source=global&cp_medium=tippy-top)

[Holiday Gift Guide

Find The Perfect RC Gift](https://www.horizonhobby.com/holiday-headquarters/?cp_source=global&cp_medium=tippy-top)

[GUARANTEED\* CHRISTMAS DELIVERY

Ground Ship Cutoff - **Today**, 12/18 @ 12PM CST](https://www.horizonhobby.com/shipping-billing-returns-info.html?cp_source=global&cp_medium=tippy-top)

[Holiday Gift Guide

Find The Perfect RC Gift](https://www.horizonhobby.com/holiday-headquarters/?cp_source=global&cp_medium=tippy-top)

[My store

Select A Store](javascript:void(0))

My store

    [Part Finder](javascript:void(0) "Find Compatible Parts for your Product")* [Sale](https://www.horizonhobby.com/horizon-hobby-rc-sale/ "Shop RC Sale Items")

        [
        
        Shop Local](https://www.horizonhobby.com/stores?showMap=true&horizontalView=true&isForm=true "Shop Local Horizon Hobby Dealers")

        [
        
        HH Signature Events](https://www.horizonhobby.com/hh-signature-events.html "Signature Horizon Hobby Events Information")
        
        [
        
        Events Calendar](https://www.horizonhobby.com/rc-events-calendar.html "Find RC Events on our Calendar")

Today's Deals

Horizon Hobby Deals

Check out all the deals on your favorite RC Product.

Shop & Save!

Shop new price drops from your favorite brands.

Spektrum Powerstage Bundles

Save a bundle when you buy together.

Part Finder
-----------

Search for compatible Parts & Accessories to complete or upgrade your product.

Brand ARRMA Axial Blade DLE Engines E-flite Hangar 9 HobbyZone Losi OS Engines Pro Boat Saito Engines Spektrum Team Losi Racing Top Flite

Product Name

SKU

Search

Search Name or Part Number

 icon-close

###### Use My Location

icon-close

Browser location service must be enabled.

Privacy Policy
==============

Last updated: January 2023

Your privacy is important to us. This privacy policy explains what personal data Horizon Hobby collects from you, through our interactions with you, and how we use that data.

Horizon Hobby offers a wide range of websites to assist customers across the globe. Please read the site-specific details in this privacy statement, which provide additional details about some of Horizon Hobby's websites.

You can freely access much of our websites without providing any personal information. But certain functions of our website, for example purchasing products, entering contests, filling out surveys, and receiving newsletters, emails, or other promotional information from us, require that you submit some personal information. We do not collect any personal information without providing adequate notice and choice.

1\. Your Rights Concerning Personally Identifiable Information
--------------------------------------------------------------

You always have the right to request information about your stored data, its origin, its recipients, and the purpose of its collection at no charge. You also have the right to request that it be corrected, blocked, or deleted. You can [contact us](https://www.horizonhobby.com/contact) at any time if you have further questions about privacy and data protection.

Learn More

##### Privacy and Data Protection

×

Many data processing operations are only possible with your express consent. You may revoke consent for these data processing operations at any time to stop future processing. An informal email making this request is sufficient. The data processed before we receive your request may still be legally processed depending on the nature of the data and Horizon Hobby's legal requirements or legitimate interest in such data.

You have the right to have data which we process based on your consent or in fulfillment of a contract delivered to yourself or to a third party in a standard, machine-readable format. If you require direct transfer of data to another responsible party, this will only be done to the extent technically feasible. Horizon Hobby may require reasonable actions of the requester, such as the use of confirmation codes, prior to delivery, to protect users' personal information from potential malicious third parties.If there has been a breach of data protection legislation, the person affected may file a complaint with the competent regulatory authorities. The competent regulatory authority for matters related to data protection in the European Union is the data protection officer of the German state in which our subsidiary, Horizon Hobby GmbH, is headquartered, Schleswig-Holstein.

Close

2\. Notice Concerning the Data Protection Officers and Party Responsible for Horizon Hobby Websites
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

The party responsible for processing data on our US-based websites intended for American and other non-European users, such as horizonhobby.com, towerhobbies.com, spektrumrc.com, axialracing.com, etc., is:

Horizon Hobby LLC  
2904 Research Road  
Champaign, IL  
61822  

Our Data Protection Officer for these US-based sites is Ben Ambrose, who can be reached through the site [contact form](https://www.horizonhobby.com/contact). 

The part responsible for processing data on our EU-based websites intended for European users, such as horizonhobby.eu, horizonhobby.de, arrmarc.com etc., is:

Horizon Hobby GmbH  
Hanskampring 9  
D-22885 Barsbüttel, Germany  
Phone: +49-40-822167800

Our Data Protection Officer for these EU-based sites is Ben Ambrose, who can be reached through the site [contact form](https://www.horizonhobby.com/contact). 

3\. Types of Data We Collect
----------------------------

Our goal is to provide you with the best and most efficient service as possible so you can get back to your hobbies. Horizon Hobby collects data to help us provide this service. We use the data that we collect about you to fulfill your product and service purchases and to create a personalized online experience. In order to better provide you with these products and services, our websites collect two types of information about users: Personally Identifiable and Non-Personally Identifiable Information.

Learn More

##### Personally Identifiable and Non-Personally Identifiable Information

×

We gather certain information about you based upon where you shop on our site in several ways. This information is compiled and analyzed on both an individual and aggregated basis. For example, this information may include the Uniform Resource Locator ("URL") of the website you came from, the URL you go to next, the browser you are using, and your Internet Protocol ("IP") address. A URL is the global address of documents and other resources on the World Wide Web. An IP address is an identifier for a computer or device on a Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol ("TCP/IP") network, such as the World Wide Web. Networks like the Web use TCP/IP to route information based on the IP address of the destination. In other words, an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the web and allows web servers to locate and identify your computer. Computers require IP addresses for users to communicate on the Internet, browse, and shop.

#### Personal Data We Collect

Personal information is requested when you order a product, register for a Wish List, enter contests or sweepstakes, fill out surveys, send us feedback, and send us mailings. For example, this information might include but is not limited to your name, billing address, shipping address, telephone number, email address, credit card or other payment information, and product details. With this information, our online catalog can fill your orders and better provide you with personalized services.

Most personal information collected by Horizon Hobby is necessary for completion of purchase orders. Other personal data is collected with your consent. Horizon Hobby works to provide users with as much relevant information as possible prior to collecting any personal data.

Under certain circumstances, we may be required to disclose your personal information in response to valid requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Close

4\. How We Collect and Use Data
-------------------------------

### Cookies

Some of our web pages include cookies. You can configure your browser to selectively or always reject cookies. But disabling or rejecting cookies may limit the functionality of this website. Cookies, which are necessary to allow electronic communications or to provide certain functions you use, are stored pursuant to GDPR Art. 6(1)(f), which allows the processing for a legitimate interest. Horizon Hobby has a legitimate interest in the storage of cookies to ensure an optimized service provided free of technical errors. Cookies stored for other purposes, such as customizing your online experience, are treated separately in this privacy policy.

Learn More

##### Cookies

×

Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer and saved by your browser. Cookies do not harm your computer and do not contain any viruses. Most of the cookies we use are session cookies that are automatically deleted after your visit. Other cookies make it possible to recognize your browser when you next visit the site.

You can configure your browser or browser plug-ins to inform you about the use of cookies so that you can decide on a case-by-case basis whether to accept or reject a cookie. Also, your browser can be configured to automatically accept cookies under certain conditions, to always reject them, or to automatically delete cookies when closing your browser.

Close

### Web Beacons

Some Horizon Hobby web pages include web beacons. Web beacons are small, graphic images on web pages or web-based documents or in email messages. We use web beacons to personalize your experience on some Horizon Hobby websites, determine the usefulness of information our services provide and analyze general user traffic patterns. Information about specific uses of web beacons on Horizon Hobby web pages can be found under the Analytics and Advertising section of this privacy policy.

### Server Log Files

The website provider automatically collects and stores information that your browser automatically transmits to us in server log files. These include the type and version of your browser, operating system used, referrer URL, the hostname of the accessing computer, time of the server request, and IP address. These data are not combined with data from other sources. The basis for data processing is GDPR Art. 6(1)(b), which allows the processing of data to fulfill a contract or for measures preliminary to a contract.

### Contact Forms

Should you send us questions via the contact form, we will collect the data entered on the form, including the contact details you provide to answer your question and any follow-up questions. We do not share this information without your permission. Therefore, we will process data you enter onto the contact form only with your consent under GDPR Art. 6(1)(a). You may revoke your consent at any time by sending an informal request via the site [contact form](https://www.horizonhobby.com/contact). We will retain the data you provide on the contact form until you request its deletion, revoke your consent for its storage, or the purpose of its storage ceases to exist. Mandatory provisions, especially mandatory data retention periods, remain unaffected by this provision.

### Registration on Horizon Hobby Websites

Some Horizon Hobby websites allow you to register with the website to access additional functions offered here. The input data will only be used for the purpose of using the respective site or service for which you registered. We will process the data provided during registration based on your consent under GDPR Art. 6(1)(a). You may revoke your consent at any time by sending an informal request via the site [contact form](https://www.horizonhobby.com/contact). We will continue to store the data collected during registration for as long as you remain registered on our website. Mandatory provisions, especially mandatory data retention periods, remain unaffected by this provision.

Learn More

##### Registration Data

×

The mandatory information requested during registration must be provided in full. Otherwise, we will reject your registration. If the registration form is rejected, we do not collect the information in the registration form fields. To inform you about important changes, such as those within the scope of our site or technical changes, we will use the email address specified during registration. You may unsubscribe from these emails using the link provided in the email.

Close

### Leaving Comments on Horizon Hobby Websites

Some Horizon Hobby websites allow you to leave comments or reviews. If you use the comment or review function on the sites, the time at which you created the comment and your email address will be stored along with your comment, as well as your username, unless you are posting anonymously. Our comment or review function may store the IP address of those users who posted. We need this information to be able to pursue actions for illegal or slanderous content. The comments and reviews are stored based on your consent under GDPR Art. 6(1)(a). You may revoke your consent at any time by sending an informal email request via the site [contact form](https://www.horizonhobby.com/contact). Mandatory provisions, especially mandatory data retention periods or obligations to maintain records

Learn More

##### Comment Data

×

On some Horizon Hobby websites, you may be able to sign up to receive the comment feed after registering or commenting. Your email address may be checked with a confirmation email. You can unsubscribe from this function at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link in the emails. The data provided by subscribing to the comments feed will be deleted. But if you have submitted comments or provided the data to us for another purpose or elsewhere, those comments or data will not be deleted. You may request deletion of this data by sending an informal email request request via the site [contact form](https://www.horizonhobby.com/contact)

Close

### Plugins

Some Horizon Hobby websites have social media or other types of plugins to improve our customer's online experience. Social media plugins allow users to engage with their social media pages. Horizon Hobby pages may include plugins to Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, Tumblr, LinkedIn, Pinterest, Snapchat, YouTube, Vimeo, or Google Maps. When you visit our site, a direct connection between your browser and the social media company's server is established. This allows the social media company to process the users' engagement with their social media plug-in. To establish this connection, the social media company receives information that you have visited our site from your IP address. Horizon Hobby has a legitimate interest in creating an engaging user experience on its webpages. Thus, the basis for data processing under the GDPR is Art. 6(1)(f). Information about each social media plugin can be found in the Learn More section of this provision.

Learn More

##### Plugins

×

#### Facebook plugins

The Facebook plugins allow users to connect to their Facebook accounts. They are operated by Facebook Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, California, 94025, USA. The Facebook plugins can be recognized by the Facebook logo or Like button on our sites. For an overview of the Facebook plugins, see [developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/](https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/)

When you visit our site, a direct connection between your browser and the Facebook server is established via the plugin. This enables Facebook to receive information that you have visited our site from your IP address. If you click on the Facebook "Like" or share button while you are logged into your Facebook account, you can link the content of our site to your Facebook profile. This allows Facebook to associate visits to our site with your user account. Please note that, as the operator of this site, we have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted to Facebook or of how Facebook uses these data.For more information, please see Facebook's privacy policy at [facebook.com/policy.php](https://facebook.com/policy.php). If you do not want Facebook to associate your visit to our site with your Facebook account, please log out of your Facebook account.

#### Twitter plugin

The Twitter plugin allows users to connect to their Twitter account. It is operated by Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA. The Twitter plugin can be recognized by the Twitter bird logo. For an overview of the Twitter plugin, see [dev.twitter.com/web/overview.](https://dev.twitter.com/web/overview)

When you visit our site, a direct connection between your browser and the Twitter server is established via the plugin. This enables Twitter to receive information that you have visited our site from your IP address. If you click on the "Retweet" button while you are logged into your Twitter account, you can link the content of our site to your Twitter profile. This allows Twitter to associate visits to our site with your user account. Please note that, as the operator of this site, we have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted to Twitter or of how Twitter uses these data.

For more information, please see Twitter's privacy policy at [twitter.com/privacy](https://twitter.com/privacy). If you do not want Twitter to associate your visit to our site with your Twitter account, please log out of your Twitter account.

#### Instagram plugin

The Instagram plugin allows users to connect to their Instagram account. It is operated by Instagram Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA. The Instagram plugin can be recognized by the Instagram camera logo. For an overview of the Instagram plugin, see [www.instagram.com/developer/](https://www.instagram.com/developer/).

When you visit our site, a direct connection between your browser and the Instagram server is established via the plugin. This enables Instagram to receive information that you have visited our site from your IP address. If you click on the "Instagram camera button" while you are logged into your Instagram account, you can link the content of our site to your Instagram profile. This allows Instagram to associate visits to our site with your user account. Please note that, as the operator of this site, we have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted to Instagram or of how Instagram uses these data.

For more information, please see Instagram's privacy policy at [instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/](https://instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/). If you do not want Instagram to associate your visit to our site with your Instagram account, please log out of your Instagram account.

#### Tumblr plugin

The Tumblr plugin allows users to connect to their Tumblr account. It is operated by Tumblr, Inc., 35 East 21st St., 10th Floor, New York, NY 10010, USA. The Tumblr plugin can be recognized by the Tumblr logo.

When you visit our site, a direct connection between your browser and the Instagram server is established via the plugin. This enables Instagram to receive information that you have visited our site from your IP address. If you click on the "Tumblr" button while you are logged into your Tumblr account, you can link the content of our site to your Tumblr profile. This allows Tumblr to associate visits to our site with your user account. Please note that, as the operator of this site, we have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted to Instagram or of how Tumblr uses these data.

For more information, please see Tumblr's privacy policy at [www.tumblr.com/policy/en/privacy](https://www.tumblr.com/policy/en/privacy). If you do not want Tumblr to associate your visit to our site with your Instagram account, please log out of your Instagram account.

#### LinkedIn plugin

The LinkedIn plugin allows users to connect to their LinkedIn account. It is operated by LinkedIn, a subsidiary of Microsoft, at LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. The LinkedIn plugin can be recognized by the LinkedIn logo on our sites. For an overview of the LinkedIn plugin, see [developer.linkedin.com/plugins](https://developer.linkedin.com/plugins).

When you visit our site, a direct connection between your browser and the LinkedIn server is established via the plugin. This enables LinkedIn to receive information that you have visited our site from your IP address. If you click on the LinkedIn "Recommend" button while you are logged into your LinkedIn account, you can link the content of our site to your Facebook profile. This allows LinkedIn to associate visits to our site with your user account. Please note that, as the operator of this site, we have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted to LinkedIn or of how LinkedIn uses these data.

For more information, please see LinkedIn's privacy policy at [www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy). If you do not want LinkedIn to associate your visit to our site with your LinkedIn account, please log out of your LinkedIn account.

#### Pinterest plugin

The Pinterest plugin allows users to connect to their Pinterest account. It is operated by Pinterest Inc., 635 High Street, Palo Alto, CA, 94301, USA. The Pinterest plugin can be recognized by the Pinterest "Pin it" logo.

When you visit our site, a direct connection between your browser and the Pinterest server is established via the plugin. This enables Pinterest to receive information that you have visited our site from your IP address. If you click on the Pinterest "Pin it" button while you are logged into your Pinterest account, you can link the content of our site to your Pinterest profile. This allows Pinterest to associate visits to our site with your user account. Please note that, as the operator of this site, we have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted to Pinterest or of how Pinterest uses these data.

For more information, please see Pinterest's privacy policy at [policy.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy](https://policy.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy). If you do not want Pinterest to associate your visit to our site with your Pinterest account, please log out of your Pinterest account.

#### Snapchat plugin

The Snapchat plugin allows users to connect to their Snapchat account. It is operated by Snap Inc., 63 Market Street, Venice, CA 90291, USA. The Snapchat plugin can be recognized by the Snapchat "Ghost" logo. For an overview of the Snapchat plugins, see [developers.snapchat.com/](https://developers.snapchat.com/).

When you visit our site, a direct connection between your browser and the Snapchat server is established via the plugin. This enables Snapchat to receive information that you have visited our site from your IP address. If you click on the Snapchat "Ghost" button while you are logged into your Snapchat account, you can link the content of our site to your Snapchat profile. This allows Snapchat to associate visits to our site with your user account. Please note that, as the operator of this site, we have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted to Snapchat or of how Snapchat uses these data.

For more information, please see Snapchat's privacy policy at [www.snap.com/privacy/privacy-policy/](https://www.snap.com/en-US/privacy/privacy-policy/). If you do not want Snapchat to associate your visit to our site with your Snapchat account, please log out of your Snapchat account.

#### YouTube plugin

The YouTube plugin allows users to view product related video content stored on YouTube servers. It is operated by YouTube, a subsidiary of Google, at YouTube LLC, 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, USA. The YouTube plugin can be recognized as the YouTube video player. For an overview of the YouTube plugin, see [www.youtube.com/yt/dev/](https://www.youtube.com/yt/dev/).

When you visit our site, a direct connection between your browser and the YouTube server is established via the plugin. This enables YouTube to receive information that you have visited our site from your IP address. If you are logged into your YouTube account, YouTube can associate visits to our site with your user account. Please note that, as the operator of this site, we have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted to YouTube or of how YouTube uses these data.

For more information, please see YouTube's privacy policy at [policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en). If you do not want YouTube to associate your visit to our site with your YouTube account, please log out of your YouTube account.

#### Vimeo plugin

The Vimeo plugin allows users to view product related video content stored on Vimeo servers. It is operated by Vimeo Inc., 555 West 18th Street, New York, New York 10011, USA. The Vimeo plugin can be recognized as the Vimeo video player. For an overview of the Vimeo plugin, see [developer.vimeo.com](https://developer.vimeo.com/).

When you visit our site, a direct connection between your browser and the Vimeo server is established via the plugin. This enables Vimeo to receive information that you have visited our site from your IP address. If you are logged into your Vimeo account, Vimeo can associate visits to our site with your user account. Please note that, as the operator of this site, we have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted to YouTube or of how YouTube uses these data.

For more information, please see Vimeo's privacy policy at [vimeo.com/privacy](https://vimeo.com/privacy). If you do not want Vimeo to associate your visit to our site with your Vimeo account, please log out of your Vimeo account.

#### Google Maps

The Google Maps plugin allows users to locate hobby stores and other relevant hobby locations. It is operated by Vimeo Inc., 555 West 18th Street, New York, New York 10011, USA. The Google Maps plugin can be recognized as the interactive overhead map. For an overview of the Google Maps plugin, see [cloud.google.com/maps-platform/](https://cloud.google.com/maps-platform/).

When you visit our site, a direct connection between your browser and the Google Maps server is established via the plugin. This enables Google Maps to receive information that you have visited our site from your IP address. If you are logged into your Google account, Google Maps can associate visits to our site with your user account. Please note that, as the operator of this site, we have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted to YouTube or of how Google Maps uses these data.

For more information, please see privacy policy of Google Maps at [policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en). If you do not want Google Maps to associate your visit to our site with your Google account, please log out of your Google account.

Close

### Analytics and Advertising

Some Horizon Hobby websites use third-party analytics and advertising services to a custom and optimized user experience from our websites and their advertising. Horizon Hobby pages may include the analytics and advertising services of Google Analytics, Google Analytics Remarking, Google reCAPTCHA, Facebook Web Beacon, or BazaarVoice Web Beacon. The collection of this data may come in the form of cookies, web beacons, or plugins. General information about how cookies, web beacons, and plugins work can be found above in the sections titled Cookies, Web beacons, and Social Media Plugins, respectively. Horizon Hobby has a legitimate interest in providing an optimized user experience from our websites and their advertising. Thus, the basis for data processing under the GDPR is Art. 6(1)(f). Information about each of the analytics and advertising services used on Horizon Hobby websites can be found under the Learn More section of this provision.

Learn More

##### Analytics and Advertising Services

×

#### Google Analytics

Some Horizon Hobby websites may use Google Analytics, a web analytics service. It is operated by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA.

Google Analytics uses cookies. These are text files that are stored on your computer and that allow an analysis of your use of the website. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there.

Google Analytics cookies are stored based on GDPR Art. 6(1)(f). The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior to optimize both its website and its advertising.

##### IP anonymization

We have activated the IP anonymization feature on this website. Your IP address will be shortened by Google within the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area prior to transmission to the United States. Only in exceptional cases is the full IP address sent to a Google server in the US and shortened there. Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this website to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity, and to provide other services regarding website activity and Internet usage for the website operator. The IP address transmitted by your browser as part of Google Analytics will not be merged with any other data held by Google.

##### Browser plugin

You can prevent these cookies being stored by selecting the appropriate settings in your browser. However, we wish to point out that doing so may mean you will not be able to enjoy the full functionality of this website. You can also prevent the data generated by cookies about your use of the website (including your IP address) from being passed to Google, and the processing of these data by Google, by downloading and installing the browser plugin available at the following link: [tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

##### Objecting to the collection of data

You can prevent the collection of your data by Google Analytics by clicking on the following link. An opt-out cookie will be set to prevent your data from being collected on future visits to this site: Disable Google Analytics.

For more information about how Google Analytics handles user data, see Google's privacy policy: [www.support.google.com/analytics/](https://support.google.com/analytics/#topic=3544906).

##### Outsourced data processing

We have entered into an agreement with Google for the outsourcing of our data processing and fully implement the strict requirements of the German data protection authorities when using Google Analytics.

##### Demographic data collection by Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics' demographic features. This allows reports to be generated containing statements about the age, gender, and interests of site visitors. This data comes from interest-based advertising from Google and third-party visitor data. This collected data cannot be attributed to any specific individual person. You can disable this feature at any time by adjusting the ads settings in your Google account or you can forbid the collection of your data by Google Analytics as described in the section "Refusal of data collection."

#### Google Analytics Remarketing

Some Horizon Hobby websites may use the features of Google Analytics Remarketing to combine with the cross-device capabilities of Google AdWords and DoubleClick. This service is operated by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA.

This feature makes it possible to link target audiences for promotional marketing created with Google Analytics Remarketing to the cross-device capabilities of Google AdWords and Google DoubleClick. This allows advertising to be displayed based on your personal interests, based on your previous usage and surfing behavior on one device (e.g. your mobile phone), and based on your usage on other devices (such as a tablet or computer).

Once you have given your consent, Google will associate your web and app browsing history with your Google Account for this purpose. That way, any device that signs in to your Google Account can use the same personalized promotional messaging.

To support this feature, Google Analytics collects Google-authenticated IDs of users that are temporarily linked to our Google Analytics data to define and create audiences for cross-device ad promotion.

You can permanently opt out of cross-device remarketing/targeting by turning off personalized advertising in your Google Account; follow this link: [www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/).

The aggregation of the data collected in your Google Account data is based solely on your consent, which you may give or withdraw from Google under GDPR Art. 6(1)(a). For data collection operations not merged into your Google Account (for example, because you do not have a Google Account or have objected to the merge), the collection of data is based on GDPR Art. 6(1)(f). Horizon Hobby has a legitimate interest in analyzing anonymous user behavior for promotional purposes.

For more information and the Google Privacy Policy, go to: [www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/).

#### Google AdWords and Google Conversion Tracking

Some Horizon Hobby websites may use Google AdWords. AdWords is an online advertising program from Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States ("Google").

As part of Google AdWords, we use so-called conversion tracking. When you click on an ad served by Google, a conversion tracking cookie is set. Cookies are small text files that your internet browser stores on your computer. These cookies expire after 30 days and are not used for personal identification of the user. Should the user visit certain pages of the website and the cookie has not yet expired, Google and the website can tell that the user clicked on the ad and proceeded to that page.

Each Google AdWords advertiser has a different cookie. Thus, cookies cannot be tracked using the website of an AdWords advertiser. The information obtained using the conversion cookie is used to create conversion statistics for the AdWords advertisers who have opted for conversion tracking. Customers are told the total number of users who clicked on their ad and were redirected to a conversion tracking tag page. However, advertisers do not obtain any information that can be used to personally identify users. If you do not want to participate in tracking, you can opt-out of this by disabling the Google Conversion Tracking cookie in your browser settings. By doing so, you will not be included in the conversion tracking statistics.

Conversion cookies are stored based on GDPR Art. 6(1)(f). The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior to optimize both its website and its advertising.

For more information about Google AdWords and Google Conversion Tracking, see the Google Privacy Policy: [www.google.com/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

You can configure your browser to inform you about the use of cookies so that you can decide on a case-by-case basis whether to accept or reject a cookie. Alternatively, your browser can be configured to automatically accept cookies under certain conditions or to always reject them, or to automatically delete cookies when closing your browser. Disabling cookies may limit the functionality of this website.

#### Google reCAPTCHA

Some Horizon Hobby webpages may use "Google reCAPTCHA.". This service is operated by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google").

reCAPTCHA is used to check whether the data entered on our website (such as on a contact form) has been entered by a human or by an automated program. To do this, reCAPTCHA analyzes the behavior of the website visitor based on various characteristics. This analysis starts automatically as soon as the website visitor enters the website. For the analysis, reCAPTCHA evaluates various information (e.g. IP address, how long the visitor has been on the website, or mouse movements made by the user). The data collected during the analysis will be forwarded to Google.

The reCAPTCHA analyses take place completely in the background. Website visitors are not advised that such an analysis is taking place.

Data processing is based on GDPR Art. 6(1)(f). The website operator has a legitimate interest in protecting its site from abusive automated crawling and spam.

For more information about Google reCAPTCHA and Google's privacy policy, please visit the following links: [www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy/) and [www.google.com/recaptcha/intro/android.html](https://www.google.com/recaptcha/intro/android.html).

#### Facebook Web Beacon

Some Horizon Hobby webpages may measure conversions using visitor action web beacons from Facebook, which is located at Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA.

The Facebook web beacon allows the behavior of site visitors to be tracked after they click on a Facebook ad to reach the provider's website. This allows an analysis of the effectiveness of Facebook advertisements for statistical and market research purposes and their future optimization.

The data collected is anonymous to us as operators of this website and we cannot use it to draw any conclusions about our users' identities. However, the data are stored and processed by Facebook, which may make a connection to your Facebook profile and which may use the data for its own advertising purposes, as stipulated in the Facebook privacy policy. This will allow Facebook to display ads both on Facebook and on third-party sites. We have no control over how this data is used.  
Conversion web beacons are used based on GDPR Art. 6(1)(f). The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior to optimize both its website and its advertising.

Check out Facebook's privacy policy to learn more about protecting your privacy: [www.facebook.com/about/privacy/](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).

You can also deactivate the custom audiences remarketing feature in the Ads Settings section at [www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/). You will first need to log into Facebook.

If you do not have a Facebook account, you can opt out of usage-based advertising from Facebook on the website of the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance: [www.youronlinechoices.com](https://www.youronlinechoices.com/).

#### BazaarVoice Web Beacon

Some Horizon Hobby webpages may measure conversions using visitor action web beacons from BazaarVoice, which is located at BazaarVoice, Inc., 10901 Stonelake Blvd., Austin, TX 78759, USA ("BazaarVoice").

The data collected is anonymous to us as operators of this website and we cannot use it to draw any conclusions about our users' identities. However, the data are stored and processed by BazaarVoice, which may make a connection to your BazaarVoice profile and which may use the data for its own advertising purposes, as stipulated in the BazaarVoice privacy policy. This will allow BazaarVoice to display ads both on BazaarVoice and on third-party sites. We have no control over how this data is used.

Conversion web beacons are used based on GDPR Art. 6(1)(f). The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior to optimize both its website and its advertising.

You can also opt out of data use by BazaarVoice by visiting their privacy policy webpage and selecting the "Opt Out" button in the Opting Out section.

If located in the European Union, you can also opt out of usage-based advertising from BazaarVoice on the website of the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance: [www.youronlinechoices.com](https://www.youronlinechoices.com/). If located in the United States, you can opt out from BazaarVoice on the Preferences Manager website of Truste: [https://preferences-mgr.truste.com/](https://preferences-mgr.truste.com/).

Close

5\. Newsletters
---------------

If you would like to receive our newsletter, we require a valid email address as well as information that allows us to verify that you are the owner of the specified email address and that you agree to receive this newsletter. No additional data is collected or is only collected on a voluntary basis. We only use this data to send the requested information and do not pass it on to third parties.  
We will, therefore, process any data you enter onto the contact form only with your consent under GDPR Art. 6 (1)(a). You can revoke consent to the storage of your data and email address as well as their use for sending the newsletter at any time, e.g. through the "unsubscribe" link in the newsletter. The data processed before we receive your request may still be legally processed.

Learn More

##### Newsletter Data

×

The data provided when registering for the newsletter will be used to distribute the newsletter until you cancel your subscription when said data will be deleted. Data we have stored for other purposes (e.g. email addresses for the members area) remain unaffected.

If you do not want your usage of the newsletter to be analyzed by us, you will have to unsubscribe from the newsletter. For this purpose, we provide a link in every newsletter we send. You can also unsubscribe from the newsletter directly on the website.

We use an email marketing system to analyze our newsletter campaigns. This allows us to determine if a newsletter message has been opened and which links you click on. We can thus find out how often various links are clicked.

In addition, we can see if certain actions take place after clicking on said links (conversion rate). We can thus determine whether the clicking of a link in a newsletter has led to a purchase, for example.

Our newsletter system also allows us to classify newsletter recipients into different categories (clustering). For example, newsletter recipients can be subdivided according to gender, personal preference (e.g. RC planes or RC cars), or customer relationship (e.g. existing or potential customer). This allows us to adapt the newsletters to the respective target groups.

Data processing is based on GDPR Art. 6 (1)(a). You may revoke your consent at any time. The data processed before we receive your request may still be legally processed.

The data provided when registering for the newsletter will be used to distribute the newsletter until you cancel your subscription when said data will be deleted from our servers. Data we have stored for other purposes (e.g. email addresses for the members area) remains unaffected.

Close

6\. Mobile Notifications
------------------------

If you would like to receive mobile notifications, we require a valid phone number capable of accepting SMS messages as well as information that allows us to verify that you are the owner of the specified phone number and that you agree to receive mobile notifications. No additional data is collected or is only collected on a voluntary basis. We only use this data to send the requested information.

We will, therefore, process any data you enter onto the contact form only with your consent under GDPR Art. 6 (1)(a) and the Telephone Consumer Protection Act. You can revoke consent to the storage of your data and telephone number as well as their use for sending mobile notifications at any time, e.g. by replying with a STOP message. The data processed before we receive your request may still be legally processed.

Sharing excludes text messaging originator opt-in data and consent. No mobile information will be shared with third parties/affiliates for marketing/promotional purposes. All the above categories exclude text messaging originator opt-in data and consent; this information will not be shared with any third parties.

7\. Payment Processing
----------------------

Horizon Hobby websites accept payments via PayPal, Inc., which is located at PayPal, Inc., 2211 North First Street, San Jose, CA 95131, USA. If you select payment via PayPal, the payment data you provide will be supplied to PayPal based on GDPR Art. 6(1)(b), processing for the purpose of completing a contract.

8\. How to Access and Control Your Personal Data
------------------------------------------------

You always have the right to request information about your stored data, its origin, its recipients, and the purpose of its collection at no charge.

You always have the right to request information about your stored data, its origin, its recipients, and the purpose of its collection at no charge.  
You may change any of your personal information in your account online at any time. Also, you may contact us to assist in changing your personal information in your account online or to change, block, delete, or provide to you any other personal information stored by Horizon Hobby. However, some past transactional and encrypted backup data may not be deleted. To make any personal data requests, please contact us and make a request via the site [contact form](https://www.horizonhobby.com/contact).

Learn More

##### Personal Data Requests

×

We encourage you to promptly update your information in your online account if it changes. You may ask to have the information on your account deleted or anonymized. However, we keep track of past purchases for legal and business-practice reasons. Thus, you cannot delete information associated with past purchases. Also, as a security measure, we back up data stored on our systems. Such prior information is encrypted, and individual records cannot be accessed unless the backup data is restored. If Horizon Hobby must restore a data backup, we will make our best efforts to fulfill the prior user requested changes to the restored data.

Close

9\. California Privacy Disclosures
----------------------------------

Personal data of California residents is processed in accordance with the California Consumer Protection Act (CCPA). Because we do not sell your personal data, we do not include an opt-out to the sale of personal data. You have the right to request us to disclose personal data that we collect, use, disclose, and sell about your household; and to request that we delete personal data about your household. If you make such request, we may be required to verify your identity under the CCPA, prior to proceeding with or during the processing of the request. These requests may be made by request via the site [contact form](https://www.horizonhobby.com/contact) or our toll-free number (800-338-4639).

We will not discriminate against you based on your decision to exercise your rights under the CCPA, as required by the CCPA.

The following provides a summary of the categories and primary sources of personal data that we collect on California residents, which is further outlined in Sections 4, 5, and 6 of this policy.

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
CA Privacy Disclosures Summary
| Category | Source | Purpose |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Name and contact info | User interaction | Provide products and support; marketing |
| Credentials | User interaction | Provide products and support |
| Payment Info | User interaction | Provide products and support |
| Demographic info | User interaction and third-party brokers | Provide and personalize products and support; marketing |
| Name and contact info | User interaction | Provide products and support; marketing |
| IP address | User interaction | Website security and integrity; website use analytics; marketing |

10\. Privacy Shield Framework
-----------------------------

Horizon Hobby complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union, the United Kingdom, and Switzerland to the United States. Horizon Hobby has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/. Horizon Hobby has further committed to cooperate with the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC) with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning data transferred from the EU and Switzerland.

You can direct any questions or complaints about the use or disclosure of your personal data by [contacting us](https://www.horizonhobby.com/contact). We will investigate and attempt to resolve any complaints or disputes regarding the use or disclosure of your personal data within 45 days of receiving your complaint.

If you are protected under EU, UK, or Swiss law and unsatisfied with the resolution of your complaint, you may contact the International Centre for Dispute Resolution – American Arbitration Association (ICDR-AAA) at http://go.adr.org/privacyshieldfiling.html for further information and assistance. You may have the option to select binding arbitration for the resolution of your complaint under certain circumstances, provided you have taken the following steps: (1) raised your complaint directly with Horizon Hobby and provided us the opportunity to resolve the issue; (2) made use of the independent dispute resolution mechanism identified above; and (3) raised the issue through the relevant data protection authority and allowed the US Department of Commerce an opportunity to resolve the complaint at no cost to you. For more information on binding arbitration, see the US Department of Commerce's Privacy Shield Framework: Annex I (Binding Arbitration).

We may transfer personal information to our third-party agents or service providers who perform functions on our behalf as described above. Where required by the Privacy Shield, we enter into written agreements with those third-party agents and service providers requiring them to provide the same level of protection the Privacy Shield requires and limiting their use of the data to the specified services provided on our behalf. We take reasonable and appropriate steps to ensure that third-party agents and service providers process personal information in accordance with our Privacy Shield obligations and to stop and remediate any unauthorized processing. Under certain circumstances, we may remain liable for the acts of our third-party agents or service providers who perform services on our behalf for their handling of personal information that we transfer to them.

11\. A Special Note About Children's Privacy
--------------------------------------------

You must be at least 18 years old to have our permission to use this site. Our policy is that we do not knowingly collect, use, or disclose Personally Identifiable Information about visitors under 18 years of age. If you are the parent or guardian of a minor under 18 years of age and believe that the minor has disclosed personally identifiable information to us, please contact us via the site [contact form](https://www.horizonhobby.com/contact) so that we may delete the minor's information.

12\. Other Important Privacy Information
----------------------------------------

This privacy policy was last changed on January 4, 2023. If Horizon Hobby makes any changes to any terms or conditions of the privacy policy, the changes will be posted in this document, so you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and to whom we will disclose it. We may change, modify, add, or remove portions of this policy at any time in accordance with the laws and regulations of jurisdictions covering our intended or expected users. Any changes will become effective immediately upon being posted unless we tell you otherwise.

HORIZON HOBBY, WHERE RC MEMORIES LIVE.

Who We Are.

At Horizon Hobby, our personal goal is to inspire dreams and build memories. We take pride in providing the best hobby store experience for our customers, whether that’s online, at RC events, or in the RC community with RC cars, RC planes, RC boats, and so much more.

Our Values.

Our purpose is simple: deliver WOW moments. By pursuing the best experience through our portfolio of RC cars, helicopters, airplanes, boats, and more, we bring the RC community together in every city, town, and country. We are radio control innovators and Driven is our middle name.

Our Promise.

Our promise to our customers is creating one-of-a-kind experiences that keeps you coming back for more. We are more than an online hobby store. Our RC cars and trucks, RC airplanes and helicopters, and other radio control products are with you at home, on the go, and with your friends. We bring the fun.

Our policies are top notch:

Sign up & save 10% on your next order!\*

Be the first to know about new products, deals, and events.

10% discount does not apply to E-Gift Cards or discounted items.

_\*Some exclusions may apply. First time subscribers only. Your discount code will be emailed to you._

 SIGN UP

Sign up for Horizon Hobby Text Alerts!

Never miss out - text **HOBBY** to **44721**[Learn More](https://www.horizonhobby.com/hh-sms-sign-up-content.html)

Shop

Support

Company Info

Legal

* * *

Copyright © Horizon Hobby, LLC

<!-- Browsers that do not support iframes --> <p>Your browser does not support iframes.</p>
